‫We added our first simple route in a extra file here to keep our app.js file lean.
‫Now as I mentioned though, this isn't even a route which we need,
‫we need to get routes in the places area but we need routes for a specific user ID or a specific place
‫ID, we also need other routes like post, patch and delete.
‫So let's work on that now,
‫let's also make sure that we only reach our places routes if the request starts with
‫/api/places as indicated on that slide and not with slash
‫nothing as it's currently the case because we also want to be able to use /api/users to later
‫reach our users routes.
‫So for that back in our application, to make sure that we only make it to these places routes, if the
‫request starts with /api/places, we have to add a filter here on this middleware in the app.js
‫file.
‫Now when using the use method, you don't have to add a path filter but you can, then this filter will
‫also not be treated as a
‫this has to be the exact path filter but as a the path has to start with the specified path filter.
‫That means that here as a first argument, we can add /api/places and Express.js will now
‫only forward requests to our places routes middleware,
‫so to the routes configured here if their path starts with /api/places. It can be longer than
‫that so it can be /api/places slash something,
‫it will still be forwarded but for example just /api/
‫would not be forwarded to places routes.
‫So with that if we change this, we make sure that if we reload here, this does not work anymore because
‫now our route here, slash nothing, actually has to be prepended with /api/places and that's
‫also important,
‫the route filter you set up here is automatically added to the filter you have here.
‫So if you want to have requests which start with /api/places, you must not repeat that here,
‫instead here you only add the path after that initial filter you have in app.js already.
‫So here that simply means just api/places/
‫should trigger this function. So here if we now enter api/places, we get our message again,
‫this works but of course whilst it's nice that this works, this isn't really the logic we need here.
‫Instead if we have a look at our plan again, we need to get route which has /users/some userId
‫in it or which just searches for a specific place ID and to practice that,
‫let's actually add a constant here in places routes, dummy places which will later in the course be replaced
‫by our database access in the end but here,
‫let's just store some dummy places for the moment and every place could have an ID, p1, could have
‫a title, for example Empire State Building, could have a description, one of the most famous skyscrapers
‫in the world, a
‫location which actually should be a nested object with a latitude and longitude
‫and here I simply use Google Maps to search for that, so I'll paste in the values, you can simply use
‫Google maps and search for the Empire State Building to then find the latitude and longitude here in
‫the URL, the thing after the lat is the latitude,
‫the thing after the comma thereafter, before the next comma is the longitude,
‫so that's what I simply pasted in here. Then the address which I'll also simply paste from Google Maps
‫and a creator field which points at a fictional user ID, because we have no real users at the moment,
‫u1 which I would say is the user who created that place. Later of course, we will have real users
‫and linked up models will have users connected to places,
‫for now we'll just work with the dummy data.
‫So now we have a place which we could try to get by its ID,
‫so actually here, I want to have a get request where the ID is part of the URL.
‫So the idea is that we send the request to api/places/p1 for example and this gives us
‫the data for the place with the ID, p1, so the ID should be encoded in the URL,
‫that's a typical pattern you see in such APIs in reality. To tell Express that we have a dynamic
‫segment which we don't know in advance because of course I can't say I want to load something for p1
‫because later we'll have more places with different IDs,
‫so to tell Express that we have a dynamic segment, where we don't know the exact value in advance but
‫where we want to be able to later use it in this middleware function and find a place by the concrete
‫value which was entered,
‫we add a colon here in our filter and then any identifier of our choice, for example place ID or just
‫pid for place ID.
‫Now Express.js accepts this route here, if I save this and I reload this URL with
‫places/p1,
‫we see we make it into this middleware function and that's great
‫but now I also want to return that place with that ID which I conveniently have here because I
‫added it as a dummy place. For that, we need to extract the concrete value that was entered for this concrete
‫request which reaches this function and Express.js has got us covered with that too.
‫We can get the place ID by using the request object and there, you will have a params property,
‫this is added by Express.js. The params property in the end holds an object where your dynamic segments
‫here will exist as keys and the value will be the concrete value the user who sent the request entered,
‫so here we can access request params.pid and get the concrete ID that is encoded in the URL.
‫Well and now we can search for a place with that ID in the dummy places array and add that to
‫the response we're sending back.
‫So here we can get our place by reaching out to dummy places and using the find method which is a default
‫Javascript array method,
‫it helps us find a specific element in an array. Find takes a function which we pass to it which will
‫be executed on every element in the array and the element that's currently looking at will be fed in to
‫the function as an argument,
‫so the place in this case which I'll just name p here in the argument to not clash with this constant
‫name. Then here in this find function, we have to return true if we're looking at the place which we want
‫to find,
‫so here I will return p.id
‫equal place ID, so I'm comparing the ID of the place I'm currently looking at and keep in mind, this function
‫here executes on all elements in this array, of course here we only have one but if we had more than
‫one it would execute on all of them and it will then return true if the ID of the place it's currently
‫looking at is equal to the ID that was part of our URL and then here instead of returning some
‫message, I can return the place here in my response.
‫This syntax here by the way can always be shortened to this, that is default Javascript, it in the end means
‫that Javascript automatically expands this to this, if the name of the property is equal to the name
‫of the variable that holds the value you want to store in the property,
‫you can shorten it. And with that if we now save this and we reload this page, you'll see indeed
‫here I get back
‫that place data, I get back that place data because I entered a valid ID.
‫If I for example would try to find the place with the ID p2, which I don't have here in my dummy places,
‫you would see I get back an empty object because there is no place which I found,
‫so there is no place added to this object. Of course in such a case where we didn't find a place, we might
‫want to handle this error differently and return of 404 error for example
‫but we'll have a look at error handling a little later,
‫for now let's leave it as it is and instead work on another route.
‫Let's implement that get/users/:uid route here and that is actually a great practice
‫for you, we'll implement it together in the next lecture
‫but here it's your job to instead write a new route that is able to accept this dynamic uid segment,
‫extract it in the middleware function and find a place where the creator has that user ID.
‫You learned everything you need for that in the last lectures,
‫so definitely try it on your own first before we then do it together in the next lecture.